Davide Buffelli

PERSONAL DATA

PLACE AND DATE OF BIRTH: Italy 30 December 1994 EMAIL: dav.buffelli@gmail.com

Address: Via Leoncavallo 10, 37131 Verona, Italy Website: https://davidebuffelli.github.io Phone: +39 3463635436 Linkedin.com/in/davide-buffelli

ABOUT ME

My university career focused on Algorithmics, and Machine Learning. A six months internship experience, where I had the chance to develop Deep Learning algorithms for the analysis of medical slides, allowed me to gain practical experience in the field and solidified my interest towards AI and Machine Learning. After my graduation and some work experience I decided to follow my passion for research with a six months period as a Research Fellow, and I am now a Ph.D student in Information Engineering at the University of Padova, supervised by Professor Fabio Vandin. My research interests lie in the development and application of Deep Learning techniques for structured data, and for complex temporal data (such as multimodal time series, and evolving graphs).

WORK EXPERIENCE

APR. 2019-SEPT. 2019

Research Fellow at UNIVERSITY OF PADOVA, Padova

Project: "Machine Learning for Temporal Data"

Supervisor: Professor Fabio Vandin.

The research project revolved around the development of novel Deep Learning frameworks for multimodal times series.

JAN. 2019-FEB. 2019

Data Scientist, Machine Learning Engineer at Machine Learning Reply, Milan

During my time at Machine Learning Reply I had the chance to work for important clients on machine learning related projects. In particular I contributed to:

- the development of a chatbot that aids financial traders in their operations.
- · the development of an automatic system for the analysis of documents and invoices.

The main technologies involved were: Python, Rasa, Google Cloud Vision, Java.

JUL. 2018-DEC. 2018

Data Science Intern at Philips Digital and Computational Pathology, Belfast

I worked in the team responsible for the development of algorithms that aid pathologists in the analysis of medical slides (inside the TissueMark application). This implied the creation, training and validation of Deep Learning models and the engineering, processing and analysis of data.

In more detail, the work I did included:

- The creation of an automatic system for the tuning of hyperparameters for Deep Learning models.
- The development of the algorithm for the identification of the appropriate tumour regions for macrodissection for lung tissue slides (which included the analysis and engineering of data and the training and validation of Deep Learning models).
- The development of technical tasks to improve the overall deep learning infrastructure.

The main technologies involved were: Python, Keras, TensorFlow.

SERVICE

• Reviewer for: RECOMB 2020

EDUCATION

Oct. 2019 - Present Ph.D Student in Information Engineering,

Università degli studi di Padova, Padova.

Supervisor: Prof. Fabio VANDIN.

FEB. 2019 Master's Degree in Computer Science Engineering,

with final grade 110/110 with honors, **Università degli studi di Padova**, Padova. Thesis: "A Deep Learning Model for Personalised Human Activity Recognition."

Advisor: Prof. Fabio VANDIN.

JULY 2016 Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology Engineering,

with final grade 107/110, Università degli studi di Padova, Padova.

Thesis: "Algorithms for the determination of node centralities in a graph."

Advisor: Prof. Andrea Alberto PIETRACAPRINA.

JULY 2013 Engineering Technician in Computer Science (Secondary School Diploma),

Istituto Tecnico Informatico "Alle Stimate", Verona | Final Grade: 94/100.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Proficient: PYTHON, JAVA

Familiar: C, APACHE SPARK, SQL, POSTGRESQL, OBJECTIVE-C, SWIFT.

I worked extensively, both in an academic and in a professional working environment, with the main Machine Learning and Deep Learning libraries such as TensorFlow, Pytorch, Keras, Pandas, scikit-learn.

LANGUAGES

ITALIAN: Mother tongue. ENGLISH: Advanced C1.